Guide to the Thomas E. Flynn Papers, 1938-1972 IBT0004
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Thomas E. Flynn Papers
circa 1938 - circa 1972
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
IBT0004
2.5 Linear Feet 3 Document boxes, 1 flat box, 8 audio cassettes.
The Thomas E. Flynn Papers is a collection of material covering the professional life of Thomas Flynn and his role in labor and unions from 1936 until his death in 1972. This collection contains correspondence, both personal and business related to the International Brotherhood of Teamsters, memos, reports, and speeches. The collection also consists of press material such as wires, journals, magazines, and newspapers that were compiled to document union activity. There are also oral history interviews that were conducted by a Flynn biographer on audio cassette.
Biographical / Historical
Thomas E. Flynn served as General Secretary-Treasurer of the International Brotherhood of Teamsters from March 1969 until his death in March 1972. A lifelong union member, born in 1906 in Chicago, IL, Flynn was involved in and instrumental to numerous labor agreements, union organizations, executive positions, and roles of leadership. In 1924, Flynn joined Local 753 of the Milk Drivers Union while driving a team of horses on a milk route. He transferred to Local 702 of the Ice Drivers Union in 1929, where he drove trucks delivering ice to cars in Chicago's freight and produce yards, as well as coal to hotels and office buildings.
In 1936 Flynn was appointed a general organizer in Indianapolis, IN for the International Union and in 1937 he was transferred to South Bend, IN. It was during this period that Flynn played a prominent role in the establishment of the Central States Drivers Council, negotiating the initial Central States Over-the-Road Agreement – one of the first area wide Teamster contracts that led ultimately to the creation of a National Freight Agreement.
General President Daniel J. Tobin selected Flynn as Executive Assistant in 1941, where he established and directed the initial affairs of the Southern Conference of Teamsters until the conference was functional and operational. Upon the retirement of Tobin in 1952, Flynn was assigned by General President Dave Beck as National Director of the National Freight Division. In October 1953, Beck selected Flynn to handle the establishment of the Eastern Conference of Teamsters.
At the 1957 Convention, Flynn was elected Vice President of the International Brotherhood of Teamsters a position to which he was re-elected in 1961 and 1966.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research.
Scope and Contents
The Thomas E. Flynn Papers is a collection of material covering the professional life of Thomas Flynn and his role in labor and unions from 1936 until his death in 1972. This collection contains correspondence, both personal and business related to the International Brotherhood of Teamsters, memos, reports, and speeches. The collection also consists of press material such as wires, journals, magazines, and newspapers that were compiled to document union activity. There are also oral history interviews that were conducted by a Flynn biographer on audio cassette.
Arrangement
Organized by topic clusters: Correspondence, International Brotherhood of Teamsters, Press.
Newspapers; Labor; Labor unions; Labor unions -- United States -- History -- 20th century; Correspondence; International Brotherhood of Teamsters; American Federation of Labor; International Brotherhood of Teamsters, Chauffeurs, Warehousemen, and Helpers of America
- AFL-CIO, undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Agreements, undated (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Biographical Information & Notes, undated (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Correspondence - Personal, 1938-1971 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Correspondence - Personal - Condolences, 1972 March 02-1972 May 02 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Correspondence - Business, 1938-1949 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Correspondence - Business, 1941-1969 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Farrell Dobbs, 1939-1940 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- International Brotherhood of Teamsters – Circular Letters, undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
- International Brotherhood of Teamsters – Decisions & Orders, 1954-1962 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- International Brotherhood of Teamsters – Financial, undated (Box 2, Folder 2)
- International Brotherhood of Teamsters – Miscellaneous, undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Miscellaneous – Personal Items, undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Miscellaneous – Programs, Receptions, undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Notes on how to respond to attacks by the McClellan Committee and AFL-CIO, author unknown, circa 1957 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Oral History Interview - Bob Flynn, 2007 January 21 (Box 2, Cassette 1)
  General
  These oral histories were conducted by Ellen Walker.
- Oral History Interview - Bob Warnock, Sr., 2007 August 17 (Box 2, Cassette 2)
- Oral History Interview - Bob Flynn, 2007 January 21 (Box 2, Cassette 3)
  These oral histories were conducted by Ellen Walker. This interview with Bob Flynn, Cassette 3 is a duped copy of Cassette 1 and is of better quality.
- Oral History Interview - Richard Charles Bell, 2007 May 07 (Box 2, Cassette 4)
- Oral History Interview - Hugh Beins, 2007 March 23 (Box 2, Cassette 5)
- Oral History Interview - Unknown, 2007 June 20 (Box 2, Cassette 6)
- Oral History Interview - Barbara Ost, 2007 June 22 (Box 2, Cassette 7)
  These oral histories were conducted by Ellen Walker. This specific interview with Barbara Ost is only recorded with Ellen Walker's portion of the interview.
- Oral History Interview - Walter Shea, 2007 July 5 (Box 2, Cassette 8)
- Press – Clippings, circa 1940 - circa 1949 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Press – Clippings, circa 1950 - circa 1969 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Press – International Teamster Photocopies, 1944-1972 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Press – Newswire, Copy, Miscellaneous, 1969-1972 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Press – Teamsters News Service, 1966-1971 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Regional Labor Newspapers, circa 1940 - circa 1970 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Reports to GEB, 1960-1963 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Speeches, undated (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Scrapbook, circa 1930 - circa 1939 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  This is a bound scrapbook including press clippings, notes, and other material.